michaelkors.ca 2015-06-12

# Privacy Policy | Michael Kors

## Privacy Policy/Your Privacy Rights 

Last updated: January 18, 2015 

This Privacy Policy applies to information that each of Michael Kors (USA), Inc. and its parent, subsidiary and affiliate entities worldwide (individually referred to herein as the “Michael Kors”, “we,” “us” or “our”) collects about you: (i) in one of our stores or otherwise offline, (ii) through purchases you make from our catalog, or (iii) on or through michaelkors.com or destinationkors.com or michaelkors.ca (or any subdomain thereof), or one of our other websites, applications or other services from which you are accessing this Privacy Policy (each referred to herein as a “Site,” and collectively, the “Sites”). This Privacy Policy describes how we collect such information, how we use it and to whom and under what circumstances we may disclose it. The personal information we collect is stored and/or controlled by Michael Kors (USA), Inc. at 11 West 42nd St., New York, New York, 10036, USA. 

We may share your personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, as further described in our Information Disclosure and Your Choices/Your Privacy Rights sections below. If you wish to opt out of such sharing, please contact [customerservice@michaelkors.com](mailto:customerservice@michaelkors.com) or [customerservice@michaelkors.ca](mailto:customerservice@michaelkors.ca), and include your name, email address and postal address in your request. 

Table of Contents (click on one of the links below to jump ahead to that section): 

• Information Collection   
  o Information You Provide to Us  
  o Site Usage Information and Other Information Collected Automatically  
  o Browser Do-Not-Track Signals  
  o Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies   
•Advertising on the Site and other Websites  
•Information Use  
•Information Disclosure  
•Your Choices/Your Privacy Rights  
•Maintenance and Processing of Information in the U.S. and Other Countries  
•Access To Your Personal Information  
•Security  
•Children’s Privacy  
•Third-Party Websites  
•Phishing, Spoofing & Other Schemes  
•Safe Harbor Certification  
•Changes to This Privacy Policy  
•Contact Us

#### Information Collection

##### Information You Provide to Us

We (or our service providers) collect information from you when you: (1) purchase products from us, whether on a Site, through a catalog or in one of our stores; (2) create an account with us, or otherwise sign up for a service or feature; (3) complete a survey; (4) participate in a sweepstakes, contest or other promotion; (5) communicate with us via third-party social media sites; (6) apply for a job with us; or (7) contact us, or otherwise communicate with us or provide information to us. The “personal information” we collect may include, for example, your name, postal address, zip or postal code, email address, telephone number, date of birth, payment information, demographic information, details on items purchased, and other information you choose to provide to us. 

In some cases, you may provide information to us about another person, such as when you purchase a gift card for someone and request that we deliver it to that person, when you share Site content or send a message to a friend through a Site or otherwise, or when you decide to ship products you purchase to someone else. In such cases, you represent that you have the authorization of such person to provide us with such information. 

We may combine the information we collect online from or about you with the information we collect offline from or about you. We may also combine your (and others’) information that we’ve collected from you (or others) with information we may receive from other sources, such as third-party social media platforms (e.g., when you choose to log in to our Site through a third-party social media platform, subject to your actions and settings thereon), address update services or co-promotion partners. **By accessing a Site, you signify your consent to the above collection of your personal information.**

When you are a creating an account for the first time on a Site with an email address that you have previously provided to us in another circumstance (e.g., in one of our stores, when signing up for our emails, by entering one of our sweepstakes or other promotions), we may recognize that email address and, once you have completed the account set-up process, you may be able to see your contact information already included in your new online account. This is happening because we have recognized your email address and, for your convenience, have added your information to your account. You can always change this information by signing into your account. 

For all users who created an online account on michaelkors.com prior to September 3, 2014, due to operational changes made to the website, certain information that was stored in your “old” site account will need to be re-entered and reset, including your account password, as well as your payment information. Your address book, however, should still be included in your account. If you have any questions, please contact us at: 1-866-709-5677 (for the U.S.) or 1-855-898-5677 (for Canada). 

##### Site Usage Information & Other Information Collected Automatically 

As part of the standard operation of the Sites, certain information is collected automatically or passively from or about you in connection with your visit to the Site. Our servers may automatically gather some of the “Site usage information” described below, or we (or our service providers) may use cookies and other tracking technologies to collect and track such information (see our Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies section below for more details). 

“Site usage information” includes, but is not limited to: (i) your browser type, device type, carrier (if applicable), device address, operating system, operating system address, IP address and the domain name from which you accessed a Site; (ii) information about your region, continent, country, city, zip code, time zone, and general location; and (iii) information about your browsing activities on and through a Site (also known as “click stream” data), such as (a) the date and time you visit one of the Sites, (b) the areas or pages of a Site that you visit, (c) the amount of time you spend viewing a Site or specific areas of a Site, (d) the number of times you return to a Site or a specific area of a Site, (e) the web sites or pages you visited prior to visiting a Site, (f) the websites or pages you visit after you leave a Site; (g) searches you have performed on the Site and on other websites that led you to our Site; (h) social plug-ins with which you have interacted on our Site; and (j) other similar Site usage data. 

We consider this Site usage information, on its own, to be non-personal in nature, unless required otherwise by applicable law. However, we may combine Site usage information about you with personal information about you, and we would consider the combined information to be “personally identifiable” or “personal information” for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.

##### Browser Do-Not-Track Signals

Some web browsers and devices permit you to broadcast a preference that you not be “tracked” online. At this time we do not modify your experience based on whether such a signal is broadcast. To learn more about browser tracking signals and “Do Not Track,” please visit [http://allaboutdnt.org](http://allaboutdnt.org/). Please note, however, that you can opt out of our (and our service providers’) use of your information for behavioral targeting of our advertisements by following the directions in the Advertising on the Site and other Websites section below. 

##### Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies 

Advertising on the Site and other Websites section below. 

> _Cookies._ A “cookie” is a small data file that is sent to your web browser and placed on your computer or device when you access a website. The cookies are then able to track your activities on the Sites and across websites. Cookies also allow us (and our service providers) to: track your activities on the Sites; track clicks, purchases and conversion; recognize your computer or device so that you are able to save your preferences and stay logged in to the Site without having to re-enter your Account credentials; deliver customized content, messages and advertising to you; preserve the contents of your shopping cart; optimize and measure the effectiveness of our advertising and emails; provide and enhance Site security and fraud detection; otherwise enhance, monitor and analyze Site usage; conduct research to improve our content, merchandise and services; and personalize your experience on the Sites. 
> 
> Most web browsers enable you to decline or block cookies (check the “Help” or “Settings” menus of your browser to learn more). While you are free to decline cookies, doing so may prevent you from taking full advantage of all features of our Site(s). Refusing cookies may also negatively impact the display or functionality of certain areas of a Site. 
> 
> **By continuing to use this Site, you consent to our use of cookies as described in this Privacy Policy, as well as ourCookie Policy (which is incorporated herein).**
> 
> _Web Beacons and Tags._ We also use web beacons (also known as “clear GIFs” or “pixel tags”), which are typically one-pixel images that are embedded on a page of a Site or in our communications, such as an email message. These technologies help us to verify when a certain page of a Site is viewed, when a message is opened and when links or other content in a message are clicked or viewed. We use the information collected through web beacons, tags and other similar technologies for similar purposes as the information collected through cookies, as described above.
> 
> _Flash Cookies/Local Stored Objects._ We may use Flash cookies and other similar technologies (referred to herein as Local Stored Objects or "LSOs"), which allow a website to store certain information locally on an individual's computer or device and then access and use that information to enhance and facilitate certain Site experiences, processes and functionality. Flash cookies and other LSOs are different from typical browser cookies (as described above), and therefore the cookie management tools provided by your web browser may not enable you to remove Flash cookies or other LSOs. To learn more about managing these technologies, visit <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/>. 

We may use third party web analytics services, such as Google Analytics and Adobe services, to help us track and analyze the use of our Site and to measure the effectiveness of our advertising, Site content and communications. These service providers’ tools, including, for example, cookies, tags and web beacons, help us to gain this understanding. To opt out of this use by Adobe, please [click here](http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html), and to opt out of this use by Google Analytics, click [here](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). 

#### Advertising on the Site and other Websites 

We also work with service providers and partner with advertising companies that use cookies, web beacons and other tools to collect information about your visits to and behavior on the Site and other websites, and then use that information to deliver targeted advertisements to you across the Internet. The information collected and used in this manner is generally, on its own, anonymous and not personally identifiable. To learn more about this practice and your choices with respect to it, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative at [www.networkadvertising.org ](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) and the Digital Advertising Alliance at [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/). To opt-out of our third-party advertising partners’ use of cookies in this manner, visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

#### Information Use 

We may use the information we collect from and about you (including both personal information and Site usage information) for a variety of purposes, including the following: 

  * to fulfill your requests for products and services and to keep you informed about your orders;
  * to provide you with targeted offers and advertising on and at the Sites; 
  * subject to your communications preferences and, where required by applicable law, subject to your consent, to contact you (via postal mail, email and the like) with promotional materials about us, our products, our services and our events, as well as about select partners; 
  * to contact you when necessary or appropriate; 
  * where appropriate, for market research and to review and improve our merchandise selections, customer service, online and offline operations and overall shopping experience; 
  * to protect the security or integrity of the Sites and our business; and 
  * otherwise, with your permission or as permitted by law. 

If you provide us with information about another person (as described above in the Information You Provide to Us section), where permitted by applicable law, we use that information to fulfill your requests and treat such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

We (and our service providers) also analyze and use Site usage information and information collected through cookies, web beacons and other tracking technologies, alone and in combination with personal information, to assess the behavior of our users, to measure the interest in and use of the Sites and communications, and to customize the Sites and our communications with you. We do this on both on an individual basis and in the aggregate. 

#### Information Disclosure 

We may disclose information we collect (including Site usage information and personal information) in the following ways, to the extent permitted by law: 

  * to our service providers and suppliers, who collect or use such information for us or on our behalf (such as website or database hosting companies, address list hosting companies, email service providers, analytics companies, distribution companies, fulfillment companies, and other similar entities that help us to operate the Sites and/or provide functionality, content and services); 
  * as necessary, if we believe that there has been a violation of the Site Terms and Conditions or any other Site policy, or if we have reason to believe that our rights or property, or the rights or property of any third party, may be or have been harmed; 
  * to respond to subpoenas or other judicial processes, or to provide information as requested by law enforcement agencies, other government authorities, or otherwise as required by law; 
  * in the event that Michael Kors or substantially all of its assets are acquired by one or more third parties as a result of an acquisition, merger, sale, consolidation, bankruptcy, liquidation or other similar corporate reorganization, where your information may be one of the transferred assets; 
  * to third-party marketers, as permitted by law, unless you direct us not to (please see the Your Choices/Your Privacy Rights section below); 
  * when you contribute to a social, community or other publicly available area or feature of the Site, the information and content that you post may be made available to the general public, depending on your settings (which is why we recommend that you do not submit or post any sensitive personal information, such as your full name, home address, phone number or other information that would enable others to contact or locate you);
  * otherwise, with your permission; and
  * as otherwise, with your permission or as permitted by law. 

Content and information that you submit on or through Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, Tumblr and other third-party platforms may appear on the Sites through feeds from and other interfaces with those platforms. We are not responsible for the information, content and/or privacy practices of any such third-party platforms. 

#### Your Choices/Your Privacy Rights 

If you would like to opt out of receiving direct mail from us, please contact us at [customerservice@michaelkors.com](mailto:customerservice@michaelkors.com). Please understand that if you opt out of receiving promotional correspondence from us, we may still contact you in connection with your Account, relationship, activities, transactions and communications with us. 

If you would like to opt out of receiving promotional emails from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions located in each such email or contact us at [customerservice@michaelkors.com](mailto:customerservice@michaelkors.com). Please understand that if you opt out of receiving promotional correspondence from us, we may still contact you in connection with your Account, relationship, activities, transactions and communications with us. 

If you would prefer that we not share your personal information with third-party marketers, please contact us at [customerservice@michaelkors.com](mailto:customerservice@michaelkors.com). Please include your name and your email and postal addresses. (Note that we never share your payment information with other marketers.) Please understand that if you do request that we stop sharing your personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, such request will only apply as of the date of your request, and we will not be responsible for any communications that you may receive from third parties that received your personal information prior to that request. In these cases, please opt out from or contact that third party directly. 

#### Maintenance and Processing of Information in the U.S. and Other Countries

Your personal and other information may be stored, transferred and processed in and to the United States and in other countries by our affiliates and our service providers. By providing personal information to us, you consent to the collection, maintenance, processing and transfer of such information in and to the United States and other countries and territories, pursuant to the laws of the United States or such other jurisdictions, which may provide lesser privacy protections than the laws of other countries, and you acknowledge that your information may thus be subject to U.S. and foreign laws and accessible to U.S. and foreign governments, courts, law enforcement and regulatory agencies. 

#### Access to Your Personal Information 

You may access any personal information you provide to us, correct or modify any such personal information, or direct us to delete or make no further use of your personal information. You can access or make certain adjustments to your account directly through your online Account, or you can contact us with your request at [customerservice@michaelkors.com](mailto:customerservice@michaelkors.com). In your request, please include your name, email and postal address, as well as your specific request and any information we may need in order to provide or otherwise process your request. 

#### Security

We have implemented measures in an effort to safeguard the personal information in our custody and control. Such measures include, for example, limiting access to personal information only to employees and authorized service providers who need to know such information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, as well as other administrative, technical and physical safeguards. Additionally, our service providers are not authorized to use or disclose your personal information for any purpose other than providing the services to us or on our behalf, or as otherwise may be required by applicable law. While we endeavor to always protect our systems, Sites and information against unauthorized access, use, modification and disclosure, due to the inherent nature of the Internet as an open global communications vehicle and other risk factors, we cannot guarantee that any information, during transmission or while stored on our systems, will be absolutely safe from intrusion by others, such as hackers. 

To provide you with increased security, access to certain personal information stored in your Account is protected with your username and password. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your Account credentials, and we strongly recommend that you do not disclose your Account username or password to anyone. We will never ask you for your password in any unsolicited communication. Please notify us immediately of any unauthorized use of your Account credentials or any other suspected breach of security.

#### Children's Privacy 

The Sites are not directed to children under the age of thirteen (13). If you are under thirteen, do not provide your personal information on or to the Site. We do not knowingly collect on the Site any personal information from children under thirteen. Users outside of the United States who are below the age of eighteen (18) (or the age of majority in the applicable jurisdiction) should not use the Sites without authorization from a parent or legal guardian. 

#### Third-Party Websites 

The Sites may contain links (which may take the form of hyperlinks, widgets, clickable logos, plug-ins, images or banners) to websites and services operated by entities other than us. This Privacy Policy does not apply to such other websites or services, so we recommend that you review their posted privacy policies so that you understand the relevant information collection, use and disclosure practices.

#### Phishing, Spoofing & Other Schemes

It has become increasingly common for hackers, cyber-criminals and other unauthorized individuals to send emails and other communications to consumers purporting to represent a legitimate company, such as a bank or an online retailer, and requesting through those communications that the consumer provide personal, often sensitive, information. Sometimes, the domain name of the sender’s email address, or the domain name of the website requesting such information, may appear to be the domain name of a legitimate, trusted company. If you receive a request to provide sensitive information (including your Account password, or any payment information) via email or to a website or individual that does not seem to be affiliated with the Sites or Michael Kors, or that otherwise seems suspicious to you, please do not respond or disclose your information. Michael Kors will never send you an email requesting that you verify any credit card information, financial information or other sensitive personal information. Please immediately report any such communication or request to us at [customerservice@michaelkors.com](mailto:customerservice@michaelkors.com). 

Additionally, Michael Kors works with customs authorities, law enforcement and legal representatives globally in an effort to prevent the sale of counterfeit Michael Kors products, both online and offline. To avoid the risk of purchasing counterfeit products, it is best to buy directly from the only official Michael Kors e-commerce website, an official Michael Kors retail store, or an authorized department store, specialty retailer or e-tailer that you know to be reputable. To report counterfeits, please email [intellectualpropertyenforcement@michaelkors.com](mailto:intellectualpropertyenforcement@michaelkors.com). 

#### Safe Harbor Certification 

Michael Kors has certified that it complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, retention, transfer and processing of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Michael Kors has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor Program, and to view Michael Kors’ certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>. The BBB EU Safe Harbor Program acts as Michael Kors' third-party dispute resolution provider, as required by the Safe Harbor Program. If you have a complaint concerning our Safe Harbor compliance, please use the BBB EU Safe Harbor Program complaint process described here: <http://www.bbb.org/us/Business-Complaints/>. 

#### Changes to This Privacy Policy 

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time and the amended policy will be posted to the Sites. Under certain circumstances (for example, in connection with certain material adverse changes to this Privacy Policy), we may also elect to notify you through additional means, such as posting a notice on the home page of the Sites or contacting you via email. 

#### Contact Us 

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy and/or about the privacy policies and practices of our service providers, please contact us at [privacy@michaelkors.com](mailto:privacy@michaelkors.com), or at: Michael Kors, 11 West 42nd Street, New York, New York 10036, Attn: Privacy Officer. 

[[Top of Page]](https://web.archive.org/browse/common/staticContent.jsp?slotId=3200001#TopofPage)
